I don't want nobody to get killed
I'll come and get you, I am always ready to fight
So don't take all of the blame
We were all swept away
I'll come and get you; I am always ready to fight
Don't take all of the weight
You always do
There will always be something you cannot control
So don't take all of the blame
We will overcome. Your salvation has begun
We were all swept away
Don't take all of the weight
You always do
No signs, no lights
There will always be something you cannot control
Such a mess all over
We will overcome
Don't kill your hopes
Your salvation has begun
You make me realize who I need
No signs, no lights
Such a mess all over
I'll be there, hold on
Don't kill your hopes
They'll change you somehow
You make me realize who I need
So where are you now?
I'll reach you by dawn
I'll be there, hold on
The shadows appear
They'll change you somehow
Illusions are born
So where are you now?
The fallen angels you run with don't know
I'll reach you by dawn
The shadows appear
It is our pain that makes us all human after all
Illusions are born
Torn old sepia photographs show
The fallen angels you run with don't know
Our fragile preious world
It is our pain that makes us all human after all
Must discard it, respond to the call
Torn old sepia photographs show
Our fragile precious world
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:鱼子酱&paper   翻译:小悠&冰蝶   校对:夜神&Lucifer   时间轴:阿水   压制:久嘉
Must discard it, respond to the call
We're All
Sinners
It's started.
始まった
Don't let them get away!
逃すな　吸血鬼どもを皆殺しにしろ
Take no prisoners!
Well, I can't say I'm surprised.
まあ　予定通りの成果は出たか…
Lieutenant Colonel.
中佐
There's something I'd like to ask you later.
後で少し　お聞きしたいことがあります
Whatever it is, I'm not interested.
俺はお前の話に興味がない
Save your breath.
だから来んな
Lieutenant Colonel!
中佐
Halt.
止まってください
This is a restricted area.
ここから先が立ち入り禁止区域です
I'm from the Japanese Imperial Demon Army's
vampire extermination unit.
私は日本帝鬼軍吸血鬼殲滅部隊に籍を置く者です
That may be so,
例え殲滅部隊の方であっても
but company officers and below are prohibited from entering.
尉官以下の人間は立ち入りを禁止されています
What is this facility used for?
ここは何の施設なのですか
I'm afraid I cannot—
お答えできません
It's a lab for the guinea pigs.
モルモットどもの実験場だよ
Watch it.
おい
What's the harm in telling her?
別に問題ないだろ
Every other troop in Shinjuku already knows.
新宿兵はみんな知ってんだから
Care to elaborate?
モルモットというのは
They're probing vampire bodies for exploitable weaknesses.
捕獲した吸血鬼どもの体を使って
弱点を探ってんだよ
So, human experimentation?
つまりは人体実験ですか
Sure, if you count those bloodsuckers as human.
あいつらが人間だっていうならそうだな
In any case, please let me through.
まあいいです　入れてください
Once again, company officers and below are—
だから尉官以下の人間は…
How about now?
これでも通れないでしょうか
The Hiiragi crest?!
柊家の…
Thank you.
では
Pardon me, but...
あの
why would a member of the
Hiiragi family remain as a sergeant?
なぜ帝鬼軍を統べる柊家の方が…
その…軍曹などという階級に…
"Sergeant" has a nice ring to it, don't you think?
軍曹って響きが好きなので
I also hold no interest for the trivial
power struggles you see within the military.
あと　軍の中でのくだらない権力争いに興味がないんです
That's how my sister died, after all.
そのせいで姉は死にましたし
For five days, I've looked for you.
5日探しました
Is that so?
Well, my bad.
そりゃご苦労だったなあ
I have a question I'd like to ask you.
少し聞きたいことがあります
And I'd rather you not.
答えないよ　だから帰れ
Scram already.
Yuu is still unconscious.
優さんがまだ目を覚ましません
What have you done to him,
Lieutenant Colonel Guren?
グレン中佐は　優さんに何をしたんですか
Or rather,
いえ　優さんで何をしようとしてるんですか
what are you planning to do with him?
You ordered me to give Yuu a special cocktail of drugs
優さんの黒鬼装備は特殊なものだから
特別配合の薬を渡せと　中佐に言われてそうしましたが
because his Infernal Arm was unique.
But didn't he go berserk because of those very same drugs?
あの暴走は　それのせいじゃないんですか
What exactly were they?
あれは何なんです
Please answer, Lieutenant Colonel!
答えてください　中佐
It's not like you to get so riled up.
お前が感情見せるなんて珍しいな
Are you upset?
怒ってんのか
Oh, well.
まあいい
So, what answer would you be satisfied with?
で　なんて答えたら納得する
Would an "I didn't do anything"
give you peace of mind?
何もしてないって答えたら安心するのか
Don't give me that!
There's no way you haven't done anyth—
馬鹿な　何もしてないわけが…
Or should I admit to human experimentation and make you angry instead?
じゃ人体実験してるって言ったら怒るのか
How can we, as the frail species we are,
survive in this collapsing world?
か弱い人間が　崩壊した世界で生き残るにはどうしたらいい
What of eliminating the Horsemen of the Apocalypse?
ヨハネの四騎士を始末するには？
Exterminating the vampires?
吸血鬼を殺すには？
Just how many were sacrificed
for your older sister, Hiiragi Mahiru,
お前の姉　柊真昼が開発した鬼呪装備は
to finish her life's work on the Infernal Arms?
何人の犠牲の上に完成した
Could we, as a species,
have survived in this world without them?
鬼呪装備なしで　人間はこの世界で生き残れたか
It's a little too late to act like we're above such things.
いまさら綺麗ごと吐かすんじゃねぇよ　ガキ
Or could it be...
それともまさかお前
that you're infatuated with Yuu?
優に惚れたか
What's with that face?
何だその顔
Frankly, I couldn't care less about
what happens between the two of you.
まあお前らがどうなろうが構わないが
But I'm not here to give you love advice, so get out.
ガキ同士の色恋を一々俺に報告しにくるなよ
帰れ
Please wait! Answer my—
待ってください
I said, out.
質問に…
か　え　れ
Oh, and those drugs?
あの薬なぁ　5日で抜けるから
They take five days to wear off,
so he'll be awake soon enough.
優の奴　目を覚ますぞ
If you love him, you'd best stay by his side.
好きなら側にいてやれよ
Yuu...
優さん　そろそろ起きてください
Please, wake up.
Yuu...
優さん
Infatuated, he says? There's no way...
惚れてる？
そんな　まさか
But please hurry and open your eyes...
でも早く　目を覚ましてくださいね
Yuu.
優さん
Time to fall back.
撤退するよ
Let go! I'm...
放せ　僕は…
I'm going to save Yuu!
僕は優ちゃんを助けるんだ
I know how you feel, but it's just not possible right now.
気持ちは分かるけど　今は無理無理
Take a look.
見なよ
Look at him being smothered
by all that sickening human greed.
人間どもの欲望が　あんなにも醜く優ちゃんに絡みついてる
Damn them...
くそ　くそ　人間どもが…
Damn them!
Damn those humans!
Well? Are you finally seething with hatred for the humans?
あは　どう　そろそろ人間が嫌いになってきたでしょ
Shut up!
黙れ
You despise both humans and vampires alike.
人間が嫌い　でも吸血鬼も嫌い
So, what are you supposed to be?
じゃあ君は一体何になるのかな
I can't wait to find out.
とても楽しみだ
It's time to go home.
じゃ　帰ろっか
Don't touch me!
放せ…
All right, playtime's over.
はい　うるさい
That's enough fun for one day.
もう十分はしゃいだだろ　黙れよ　ガキ
Not a single peep out of you, child.
Curse detoxification is complete.
鬼呪の毒の除去が　完了しました
These are the first tears I've shed ever since I became a vampire.
涙なんか　吸血鬼になってから流したことなかったのに…
I gotta say, that one human
sure did a number on us.
いやぁ　たかが人間ごときにひでぇ目に遭ったな
How's your injury, Mika?
傷はどうだよ　ミカ
You got the worst of it.
お前一番派手にやられただろ
Silent treatment again, newbie?
新入りの分際でまた無視かよ
Speaking of, what was that monster?
しかし…何だったんだろうな　あの化物は
Who knows?
ああ　あれなぁ
It's been raised as a concern
within the Progenitor Council.
上位始祖会でも　問題になってるらしいぞ
What?
Something about the humans studying
forbidden magic that could end the world.
なんでも人間どもが世界を滅ぼしかねない禁忌の研究に手を出してるって
I think they called it...
確か…
the "Seraph of the End."
「終わりのセラフ」とかいう…
Apparently, our true goal in Shinjuku was to retrieve that scary thing.
今回の新宿襲撃も　あれの回収が目的だったんだってさ
Oh?
So I take it the mission was a failure?
じゃあ作戦失敗か
No idea.
さてね　指揮取ってたフェリド様は
Lord Ferid was in command,
but I sometimes haven't the
slightest clue what's on his mind.
そもそも何考えてるか分かんない所あるし
I don't know much...
失敗かどうかは判断できないけど
but maybe you do.
でもお前は何か知ってるんじゃないの
You know who that monster was, right?
知り合いだったんだろう　あの化物と
That's why you're Queen Krul's favorite.
だからお前はクルル様のお気に入りなのか
Hyakuya Mikaela,
百夜ミカエラ　お前は何者なんだ
just who are you?
If you don't feel like answering,
we can just find out for ourselves.
答えないなら調べてもいいんだぞ
Who am I?
何者　何者か
Good question.
Y-You're not human anymore?
お…お前…もう…人間じゃないのか
Shouldn't my looks give it away?
僕が何者か
そんなの見れば分かるじゃないか
I'm just your average, ugly vampire.
ただの醜い吸血鬼だよ
The hell?
何だよそれ
Hyakuya Mikaela.
百夜ミカエラ様
Third Progenitor Krul Tepes wishes to see you.
第三位始祖　クルル・ツェペシ様がお呼びです
Please make your way to the
Royal Audience Chamber immediately.
至急　「王の間」にお越しください
Would you look at that?
ほら　呼び出しだぞ　女王のお気に入り
The queen's calling for her pet.
おい　与一　起きろ
Hey, Yoichi!
Wake up!
一体どうなってる
What's going on?!
ゆ　優くん　目が覚めたの
Yuu! I've been waiting for you to wake up!
Same here!
そりゃこっちのセリフだ
何がどうなってん…
What the hell happen—
よかった
Thank goodness!
Hey!
おい　質問に答えっ…
Answer my quest—
I need to let the others know.
みんなに教えなきゃ　すぐ呼んでくるね
I'll be right back!
Hey, hold on!
お　おい　待てって
あいつらは　みんな無事なのかよ
Are they...
Is everyone okay?
それ心配
Is that concern I see?
別に　そっ…そういうわけじゃ
Not really, I'm just...
安心して
Don't worry.
Everyone else is fine.
無事じゃなかったのは優くんだけだから
そうか
I see.
優くん　7日も昏睡状態だったんだよ
You were in a coma for seven days.
7日　マジで
Seven days?!
Seriously?
マジで　だから伝えてくるね
Seriously.
So I'm gonna let everyone know, okay?
そっか　無事か
What a relief...
They're okay.
よかった
I'm glad.
ミカ
Mika...
お前が生きてたのも　夢じゃないんだよな
You being alive wasn't a dream either, right?
嘘だろ　お前…本当に
I can't believe it.
You're really...
泣き虫君の部屋はここですか
Is this the crybaby's room?
ここみたいですね
I guess it is.
いいですよ別に　そりゃ泣くでしょう
It's fine.
It's okay to cry.
家族が生きてたんですから
You found your family, after all.
でもよかった　優さんが目を覚ましてくれて
I'm glad that you're awake.
何がどうなってんだ
What's going on?
俺…途中から記憶がないんだけど
I don't...
remember anything.
全然覚えてないんですか
Nothing at all?
うん
Yeah.
そうですか
I see.
ま　優さんは途中で眠いって言って寝てましたからね
Well, basically, you said you were sleepy and took a nap during the fight.
What?
嘘だろ
Are you serious?!
もちろん
Of course not.
優さんは突然気絶しました
You suddenly fell unconscious,
and we were all on the verge of annihilation.
部隊は壊滅の危機ですが
But then reinforcements soon arrived,
そこへ援軍が来たんです
柊暮人中将及び柊深夜少将率いる　渋谷本隊が
with Lieutenant General Kureto
and Major General Shinya leading the main unit.
じゃあ　吸血鬼どもは
And the vampires?
貴族を除く一般吸血鬼はかなり殺せました
Nobles aside, we were able to deal with many of the normal ones.
数匹は捕獲も出来ました
We also captured a few,
まぁ　それでも大半には逃げられましたが
but many were able to escape.
それじゃ
Then...
ミカさんですか
Wondering about Mika?
どうなった
What happened?
ミカさんは
Mika was...
遠慮しなくていい
Feel free to just say it.
ミカが敵だろうが　味方だろうが
Whether Mika's a friend or foe,
生きててさえくれりゃ　それで十分だから
as long as he's alive, that's enough for me.
だから　事実だけを教えてくれ
So just give it to me straight.
ミカさんは
Mika was...
吸血鬼に連れ去られました
taken by the vampires.
そうか
I see.
はい
Yes.
分かった　ありがとう
Got it.
Thanks.
と言って　病院を脱走して一人で吸血鬼の都市に乗り込んだりしないでくださいね
Or so you say, but don't let me catch you leaving
the hospital to raid the vampire city all on your own.
Yeah, yeah.
分かってるよ
今はあいつが生きてるのが分かっただけで　十分だ
Right now, knowing he's alive is enough for me.
安心しました
Good to know.
俺が抱えて走る
I'll carry him there!
どこ連れて行きゃいい
Where do we need to go?
一先ず臨時拠点だ　急げ
For now, the temporary base.
Hurry!
「ミカ」「優ちゃん」
Mika...
and Yuu...
家族　か
Family, huh?
シノア
Shinoa.
Oh, yes?
はい
心配してくれて　ありがとう
Thanks for worrying about me.
はい
You're welcome.
お前
You...
Wh-What? Wait...
これ　大丈夫だったのか
This injury...
Are you okay?
Oh, that?
それのことですか
ええと　はい　ちょっと血を吸われただけで
Um, yes, they were just feeling a bit thirsty.
おい　馬鹿優　やっと目を覚ました…か
'Sup, idiot?
Finally awake, are...
you...
Y-You two!
お前ら　一体何をやっている
What the hell are you doing?!
Um, no, it's not what it looks like!
いえいえいえいえいえいえ
今吸血鬼に噛まれた傷を見せてたところで
I was just showing him where the vampire bit me.
Wait, didn't you get bitten too?
お前もじゃねぇか　大丈夫だったのかよ
Are you okay?
そういうことか
So that's what it was...
病院の中で騒ぐんじゃねえよ
Quiet in the hospital.
Who do you think you are?!
お前　何なんだ
何だよてめぇ　元気そうじゃねぇか
What the hell's this?
You look perfectly fine to me.
心配かけたな
I'm sorry I worried you.
What?
なんでてめえなんかの心配俺がするんだ
Why would I worry about you?
とか言って　途中君月さんも甲斐甲斐しく優さんの看病してましたけどね
Oh, please.
You were fussing and hovering over him the entire time.
What?!
Don't make shit up!
ふざけたこと言ってんじゃねえぞ　何時俺がそんなことした
When did I do that?!
思いっきりしてたよ　君月くん
You totally were, Kimizuki.
What was that?!
みんな　ちょっといいか
Mind if I say something, guys?
なんだ
What is it?
Sure.
はい
Yes?
ありがとう　心配かけた
Thanks. Sorry for all the trouble.
あと　全員生き残ってよかった
I'm glad you're all alive.
俺は　仲間に恵まれてるな
I've been blessed with good friends.
おいおいおいおい　これまだ治療が要るだろ
Wait, what?
I don't think he's recovered yet.
明らかに頭とか打ってるな
It's clear he hit his head or something.
いやいや　実は優くん最初からいい子だったよ
Oh, no. Yuu was a gentle, kind soul from the start!
I sure wish he would stop acting like a saint.
いい子ちゃんアピールはやめてほしいですよねぇ
I'll take you all on!
お前ら　ぶっ飛ばすよ
まあ　でもまだ休めよ
Anyway, stay in bed for now.
少し休暇があるらしいしな
We're still on a break.
休暇
A break?
はい　優さんが本調子に戻るまでは
Yes.
Until you make a full recovery,
the Hiiragi Shinoa unit will be taking a few days off.
柊シノア隊はお休みだそうです
お休みか
A break, huh?
一刻も早くミカさんを救いに行きたいのは分かりますが
I understand you want to rescue Mika as soon as possible, but...
いや　これ以上迷惑かけるわけにはいかないからな
Nah.
I don't want to cause any more trouble,
大人しく休むよ
so I'll behave myself and rest.
じゃ俺　飲みもんでも買って来るわ
I'll go fetch us some drinks.
さすが君月さん　妹思いの看病上手
That's our Kimizuki!
A loving brother and friend.
うるせいな
Oh, shut up.
僕も行くよ　君月くん
I'll come with you!
一方　女の子なのにな～にもできない
Meanwhile, our girl Mitsu here hasn't lifted a finger!
がさつなみっちゃんもさすがです
お前も女の子なのに何もしてないだろうが
That's rich, coming from another girl
who hasn't done crap!
私は隊長だからいいんです
I'm babysitting the entire unit, so I'm excused.
Analytical Report
仲間は誰も死ななかった
None of my friends died.
ミカは生きていた
Mika is alive.
なんだよそれ
Really? What did I do to deserve such good luck?
そんないいことばっか起きていいのかよ
でも　生きてんならこっちのもんだ
But if he's alive, then I can rest easy at night.
ミカ
Mika...
優ちゃん
Yuu...
俺が必ずお前を
I swear I will...
僕が必ず君を
救う
...save you.
いや　しかし笑えるほど順調に来てるよね
Well, I must say.
It's almost amusing how smoothly things are moving.
相変わらず暴走していく　君たち人間の欲望に
As always, the greed of the human species
spirals out of control,
全てを侮る僕たち吸血鬼の傲慢さ
just as we vampires fall prey
to our own arrogance.
そうは思わない　僕の楽しいパートナー君
Don't you agree, partner?
無愛想だなあ
Oh, lighten up.
はいこれ　こっちの研究資料
This is our research data.
そうだ　忘れてた…
Ah, that's right. I almost forgot...
馴染めた白　鳥がご隅　鼓動獲たツボミも
najimeta shiro torikago sumi
I used to like the light, my corner of the cage
kodou eta tsubomi mo
I'm a flower bud made flesh
置き去り声　眩めた　記憶の影
okizarigoe kurameta kioku no kage
Blinding memories cry after me
I need your blood
i need your blood
You really love 唱える
you read love tonaeru
You speak of love to me
足掻く　Red Light
agaku red light
The red lights dance
嗅ぎ分けた音　音と
kagiwaketa neon to
The neon lamps
こじ開けたReasonが
kojiaketa reason ga
and the madness of the world
ただ平行に並ぶ
tada heikou ni narabu
share a vanishing point
Come on break it down for me!
Come on, break it down for me
come on, break it down for me
A river will flow
a river will flow
KEYがない「欲しい」でも　利害鳴る鈴
My desires remain unfulfilled
key ga nai hoshii demo
rigai naru suzu
A melody of ups and downs
懺悔さえ乾いた　４拍子が　奏でた意図を辿る
rigai naru suzu
zange sae kawaita yonbyoushi ga
Our song follows the sheet of our will,
kanadeta ito wo tadoru
no longer capable of penance
木漏れ日の　赤が　騒ぐ
kanadeta ito wo tadoru
Crimson beams assault my vision
komorebi no aka ga sawagu